Chris Wallace award-winning product design executive

TWITTER

EMAIL

WEBSITE

PHONE

@chriswallace

chriswallace7@protonmail.com

chriswallace.net

972-837-7267

Professional Summary

Emmy-nominated founder and design leader with 16+ years of leadership in product and web design. Established record of pioneering innovative digital experiences for high-profile tech and media organizations including Google, Microsoft, Facebook, ESPN, The Boston Globe, and AMC Networks. Former agency executive at 10up, Lift UX (acquired).

Work Experience

Chief Experience Officer

UltraDAO Studios // 2021 - Present // Remote

Founded a bootstrapped decentralized web3 creative studio developing entertainment media IP, digital products and blockchain-based collectibles. Built and managed a team of artists, engineers, and creative production specialists. Led a range of award-winning creative projects and drove multi-million dollar revenue within the first six months.

Vice President, Experience Design

10up // 2017 - 2021 // Remote

Matured the design discipline at an international agency of 200+ across three continents and 16 countries. Managed 20 leaders and ICs across user experience and visual design. Established content design practice and implemented org-wide design strategy.

Clients: Facebook, Microsoft, Google, The Boston Globe, ESPN, The White House

Principal Creative, Founder

Lift UX (acquired) // 2009 - 2017 // Remote

Founded a UX design studio crafting digital products and WordPress websites for clients. Launched interactive second-screen apps for acclaimed TV series, earning two Emmy nominations in the process. Managed a compact yet effective team of full-time and contract designers, elevating website traffic for the product division to two million monthly visitors. Acquired by 10up in 2017.

Clients: The Walking Dead, Mad Men, Breaking Bad, SundanceTV, IFC Films, The Next Web

Front-end Developer

Enterprise Rent-A-Car // 2007 - 2009 // Clayton, MO

Developed front-end interfaces for B2B applications and B2C websites, working closely with UX designers and Java engineers to roll out new applications. Handled weekly deployments for enterprise.com and other customer-centric platforms, while providing QA support for monthly release cycles.

Senior E-Commerce Web Designer

Network Solutions // 2006 - 2007 // Belleville, IL

Designed and developed front-end code for e-commerce storefronts for small businesses, maintaining stringent project timelines and adhering to client specifications.

Webmaster

Saint Louis Christian College // 2005 - 2006 // Florissant, MO

Primary web content owner, designed, developed, and maintained the college's online presence. During my tenure, the college experienced 60% growth, reaching full campus capacity the following year.

Skills

- * Design Management
- * Strategic Planning
- * Hiring & Personnel Management
- * Creative Direction
- * Design Systems
- **★** WordPress Design & Development
- * Resource Management
- * Professional Development Planning
- * Design Operations

- * Product Design
- * Visual & Brand Identity
- * Web3 (Blockchain & NFTs)
- * AI + Design Tooling
- * Information Architecture
- * Visual Design & Prototyping
- * Front-End Engineering
- * E-commerce Design
- * IP Development

Education

Missouri State University

Graphic Design // 2004 // Springfield, MO

Attended Missouri State University (formerly Southwest Missouri State) for Graphic Design.

Saint Louis Christian College

Religious Studies // 2002 - 2004 // Florissant, MO

Attended Saint Louis Christian College with a focus on Religious Studies.